H. IMDATH AHAMED

Mobile: +91 96884 47057 E-mail: imdathahamed@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

Merchandiser, Sourcing, Quality control and shipping Coordinator with 11 years of experience in Liaison office, Buying house and in a manufacturing environment. Applies strong analytical and critical thinking skills to solve complex operational problems in the factory.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Working with Polyconcept Trading (Shanghai)Ltd, in Chennai.TamilNadu. India- as a Merchandiser, QCI,
Sourcing & Shipping Coordinator at the moment from August 2022 until the present.

About Company:-

Global Buying Services for their Promotional brand based in Europe - PFCI & USA – PCNA is provided by Polyconcept Trading (Shanghai) Ltd.

 Worked as a Senior Merchandiser in Synergistix (India) Pvt Ltd, Chennai. Tamil Nadu. India from January 2019 to July 2022.

About Company:-

Synergistix (India) Pvt Ltd is a Buying office representing companies located in US, UK, Canada, Israel, Australia, Korea, New Zealand & China.

 Worked as a Senior Merchandiser in SMITA Exports Pvt Ltd., Chennai. Tamil Nadu. India from February 2016 to December 2018.

About Company:-

SMITA EXPORTS PVT LTD is a Manufacturer and Exporter of Goat Finished Leather

Worked as an Administrator & Branch Head in SSI Agro chemicals Pvt Ltd., Kurnool. Andhra Pradesh.
India from July 2014to November 2015.

About Company:-

SSI Agro Chemicals Pvt Ltd is a Manufacturer of Agricultural chemicals (i.e., pesticide and fertilizer)

Worked as a Microbiologist–(cum) - Quality Controller & Production Supervisor in Sulax Industries.,
Sathyamangalam. Tamil Nadu. India from May 2012 to April 2014.

About Company:-

Sulax Industries is a Manufacturer & Distributor of Packaged Drinking Water Company

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Serving as the point of contact for my international team and the vendor.
- I will take care of all aspects of product merchandising from sourcing to inspection.
- Sourcing new factories that meet our needs, conduct pre-audit on QMS and validate.
- Specialties in production handling and rectifying all the technical problem in production.
- Having wide knowledge of manufacturing in stainless steel, wooden items, marble items, home decors, stationery, and home textiles.
- Preparing material and production status for the factory and following it up on daily basis.
- Ensuring all activity is accurate and timely recorded on critical path.
- Presenting the status to the management on bimonthly report.

H. IMDATH AHAMED

Mobile: +91 96884 47057 E-mail: imdathahamed@gmail.com

- Interacting with factory on regular basis to know details on the running order and much more.
- Effectively communication with all relevant personnel involved with client account, to ensure a seamless and uncomplicated workflow.
- Preparing inspection report based on FRI inspection for shipment approval at factory located in Tirupur, Madurai, Karur, Sivakasi, Mumbai, Delhi & Kolkata.
- Having experience in conduction midline inspection and final inspection based on AQL.
- Ensure that all project-related data is accurately, consistently reviewed, updated, and readily available.
- Work in collaboration with all stakeholders to deliver product that is accurate and under their expectation.
- Act as primary contact between factory and freight forwarders for timely delivery.
- Vendor performance analysis and CAPs and claim follow up with client.
- Lead QMS audit and upgrade vendors on the same to reach targets.
- Coordination with both BU in Europe and USA for monthly meetings.

EDUCATION DETAILS

- Master of Business Administration (MBA) in HR from Bharathiar University passed out in the year 2016.
- Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Biotechnology & Advanced Zoology from Erode Arts & Science College passed out in the year 2012.

PRODUCTS HANDLED

- Bags
- Drinkware
- Hardgoods
- Stationery Products
- Finished Leather
- Garments, and
- Home Textiles

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Improved the DOT & PLT of the vendors (DOT- from 70% to 95%), PLT-100 days to 65 days)
- Improved QMS audit score of factories from 60 to 85 using Best Practice Guide
- Followed 5S with vendors through QMS audit.

TOOLS USED & HIGHLIGHTS

- Microsoft Office
- Tally ERP
- SAP
- QMS Audit
- Quality Inspection (IQC, IPQC, FQC)
- Mentoring and Training
- New Vendor Sourcing
- Process Improvement Strategies
- International shipping follow up in Taiwan, Vietnam, Cambodia, Thailand, Bangladesh & South Korea

H. IMDATH AHAMED

Mobile: +91 96884 47057 E-mail: imdathahamed@gmail.com

CHARACTERISTIC QUALITIES

- Simple, self-motivated, and always responsible.
- Positive attitude and open-minded.
- Hardworking and dedicated worker and will never balk at any task. Most importantly will make sure to complete the stipulated tasks within the given time frame.
- Quick learner able to be a part of team or lead the team.
- Try my best to adapt to different situation in the company.
- Ability to work under pressure to meet deadlines and solve problems.
- Ability to learn any new skills that are required and to be challenged.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Participated in NATIONAL SOCIAL SERVICE IN BHARATHIYAR UNIVERSITY COIMBATORE
- Participated in 2nd Symposium on Animal Welfare &Conservation in memory of late Dr.Ravi Sankaran, Renowned conservation ecologist &former director of SACON, Coimbatore, towards animal welfare fortnight celebration held at Nirmala College For Women, Coimbatore
- Member in Blood Donating Group
- Event Management (Conducting Blood Campaign)

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 24-10-1991

Language Known : Tamil, English, Malayalam, Telugu (Understandable) & Hindi (Understandable)

Present Address : 3/48, Nakeeran St, Mogappair East, Chennai -600037.

Permanent Address : No: 19, Thiruveeka Joint Street, P. Puliampatti. Erode District – 638459.

Passport No : L8677292, Expiry Date: 27/04/2024

Skype Id : imdathahamed_1

LinkedIn : www.linkedin.com/in/imdathahamed2410

Should you have any questions please feel free to call me at the number listed above / to contact me via the email address listed above. Your consideration is greatly appreciated.

Thanking you most sincerely for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

H.Imdath Ahamed.